<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Océane Cassan</title>
    <link>/author/oceane-cassan/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/oceane-cassan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Océane Cassan</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Océane Cassan</title>
      <link>/author/oceane-cassan/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster - JOBIM</title>
      <link>/talk/jobim_poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/jobim_poster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-throughput transcriptomic datasets are often examined to discover new actors and regulators of a biological response. To this end, graphical interfaces have been developed and allow a broad range of users to conduct standard analyses from RNA-seq data, even with little programming experience. Although existing solutions usually provide adequate procedures for normalization, exploration or differential expression, more advanced features, such as gene clustering or regulatory network inference, often miss or do not reflect current state of the art methodologies. We developed a user interface called DIANE, designed to harness the potential of multi-factorial expression datasets from any organisms through a precise set of methods.
DIANE interactive workflow provides normalization, dimensionality reduction, differential expression and ontology enrichment. Gene clustering can be performed and explored via configurable Mixture Models, and Random Forests are used to infer gene regulatory networks. DIANE also includes a novel procedure to assess the statistical significance of regulator-target influence measures based on permutations for Random Forest importance metrics.  All along the pipeline, session reports and results can be downloaded to ensure clear and reproducible analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate the benefits of DIANE using a recently published dataset describing the transcriptional response of Arabidopsis thaliana under the combination of temperature, drought and salinity perturbations. We show that DIANE can intuitively carry out informative exploration and statistical procedures with RNA-Seq data, perform model based gene expression profiles clustering and go further into gene network reconstruction, providing relevant candidate genes or signalling pathways to explore. Our novel approach to sparsify the output of Random Forests regulatory weights is benchmarked against two databases of known regulatory interactions in A. thaliana and E. coli, and shows more precise predictions as compared to a naive hard-thresholding of Random Forests importance metrics. DIANE is available as a web service (&lt;a href=&#34;https://diane.bpmp.inrae.fr&#34;&gt;https://diane.bpmp.inrae.fr&lt;/a&gt;), or can be installed and locally launched as a complete R package. For this jobim poster session, we propose a live demonstration of the tool, by conducting a standard analysis of the package&amp;rsquo;s companion dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster - International Plant System Biology workshop</title>
      <link>/talk/ipsb_poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/ipsb_poster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change comes as a major challenge in agroecology, notably through the sustained rise of atmospheric CO2 levels. Field studies conducted worldwide have shown that exposure to elevated CO2 leads to a marked depletion in the content of most nutrients in crops, deteriorating their nutritional value and representing a serious threat to human health. Literature suggests that even though biomass is increased by elevated CO2, the observed mineral depletion is not only due to carbon dilution, but also to negative perturbations on nutritional signaling pathways. However, most of the regulatory mechanisms causing a negative effect on plant mineral nutrition under elevated CO2 remain to be identified. Therefore, in order to preserve food security for the future in a context of sustainable agriculture with low inputs, it is crucial to understand how elevated CO2 impacts regulatory circuits associated with plant mineral nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this purpose we generated transcriptomic datasets in which Arabidopsis plants were exposed to elevated CO2, low nitrate conditions and iron starvation in a combinatorial fashion. We used it first to investigate how gene expression is being reprogrammed in roots under high atmospheric CO2, and how this response interacts with nutritional starvation pathways. We notably show that elevated CO2 significantly disrupts signaling pathways associated with nitrate and iron starvations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we reconstructed a genome-wide network of candidate regulatory interactions of the response to elevated CO2 under low nitrate. We made use of Random Forests, a machine learning approach allowing the extraction of candidate regulatory links between regulators and genes, based on their expression profiles. We developed a statistical procedure to refine this output into a sparse network by empirical tests on the inferred gene pairs. This approach led us to identify several potential regulators of plant response to nutritional limitations under elevated CO2, of which we are currently characterizing the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altogether, our results indicate that elevated CO2 alters plant response to nutrient starvation, by deregulating nutrient uptake adaptive strategies in roots. This finding, along with the identification of candidate genes from network analysis pave the way for strategies aiming at maintaining plant nutritional value despite the progression of climate change, in a sustainable perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
rcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 15+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic comes with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can  choose their preferred mode - click the sun/moon icon in the top right of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/customization/#custom-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;customizable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-web-browser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;install on your computer using &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;install on your computer by downloading the &lt;strong&gt;ZIP files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;install on your computer with &lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;personalize and deploy your new site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;View the Update Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
